I am both a prince
我既为皇子
And a subject
也是臣子
How could there be
怎么会有
Reason to disobey orders?
不听调遣的道理
This is my military seal
这是我的虎符军印
I give it to General Chen
交予陈将军
I hope General Chen
还望陈将军
Will fulfill his duties diligently
用心履职
Do not disappoint the soldiers
切莫辜负了众将士啊
Please rest assured, Your Highness
请殿下放心
I
臣
Will not disappoint Your Highness
定不负殿下所望
He's so obedient
他就这么听话
Just handed over military command like that
就这么把兵权交了
In my heart
我这心里啊
I'm uneasy
不安呐
A dog that bites
咬人的狗
Never barks
从不叫唤
In the past
昔日
When Prince of Jin was imprisoned
晋王入狱时
I advised Your Highness
我曾劝殿下
To go all the way
一不做二不休
But Your Highness then
可殿下那时
Hesitated
却是犹豫了
Chancellor Chen
陈相
Don't tease me
你莫要拿我打趣了
Give the order
下令吧
Immediately order Qingzhou Army to break camp
即刻命令庆州军拔营
Move toward the capital
往皇城靠拢
Also
还有
Send Chen Ying
给陈应
Another letter
再传一封信
Yes
是
This is just my personal letter
这只是我的家书
Why was it opened?
为何被人拆过
General Chen Ying ordered
陈应将军吩咐
All correspondence in the army
军中一应信件往来
Must first be sent to him for review
都要先交送他查看
Chen Ying
陈应
Think clearly
你想想清楚
Whose orders do you follow?
你到底听谁的命令
I only follow military orders
末将只听军令
Who promoted you all this way?
这一路以来是谁提拔的你
I really misjudged you
我倒真是看错人了
Get out
出去
Your Highness
殿下
Let's have a good drink tonight
晚上好好喝一顿
Sir
大人
The volunteer army families
义军的家人
All depend on Yiyang's compensation to survive
都指着弋阳的抚恤活命
Really can't delay any longer
真的不能再拖了
Want to talk? Fine
想谈可以啊
After you're cleaned up
待会洗干净了
The heir
世子
The princess consort
王妃
Are both in the capital
都在京中
I must consider them
我必须要考虑到他们
Right now, no matter what
现在无论如何
Cannot act rashly
不能擅动
Who?
谁
Your Highness
殿下
It's me
是我
Zhu Yuanzhi
朱元之
What are you doing?
你干什么
At this time
这种时候
You kill Chen Ying's men
你杀陈应的人
Isn't that making things worse?
还不嫌事大吗
Your Highness
殿下
Look who's here
你看谁来了
This old minister
老臣
Finally sees you
终于见到你了
Please rise quickly
快快请起
Huiji is a thousand li
会吉距弋阳
From Yiyang
千里之遥
How did you come?
你怎么来了
Since Your Highness's victory
自殿下得胜以来
The situation has been crystal clear
局势便已洞若观火
So I
于是臣
Left Huiji Commandery early
早早就从会吉郡抽身
Secretly returned to the capital to plan
密返京中布局
Your Highness
殿下
This is what I intercepted from the capital
这是我从京城截获的
A secret letter from Chen Dao to Chen Ying
陈导发给陈应的密信
This is critical
事关重大
Quickly summon Xie Xuan
你赶紧把谢玄
And Uncle Qiu together
和邱叔一起召来
Zhu Yuanzhi, how dare you
朱元之你大胆
My sister and the heir are still in the capital
我姐和世子可还在京中
Are you trying to harm them?
你要害他们不成
Brother-in-law
姐夫
Don't be impulsive
别冲动啊
Father
爹
Say something
你说句话呀
Your Highness
殿下
Though somewhat offensive
虽有些冒犯
I must speak some words
但是臣有些话不能不讲了
If Your Highness hesitates further
若殿下再犹豫下去
Then we'll be like fish on a chopping block
那就等着人为刀俎
At others' mercy
我为鱼肉啊
Enough, Zhu Yuanzhi
够了朱元之
Do you know what you're saying?
你知道你在说什么吗
I know Your Highness's concerns
我知道殿下的顾虑
But if Your Highness truly dies here
但殿下如果你真的死在这
Then the princess consort
那王妃
And the heir
和世子
Can they have a good outcome?
他们能有个好下场吗
Your Highness
殿下
Strike first to gain advantage
先下手为强啊